Guide to the Stanford University, Program in Creative Writing, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Program in Creative Writing, records
1982-2010
SC1235
Stanford University. Program in Creative Writing..
4 Linear feet 8 boxes
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of photographs and recordings of speakers at events sponsored by the Stanford University, Program in Creative Writing, including the Jean and Bill Lane Lecture Series and the President's Reading Series.
Access Terms
Audiotapes.; Creative Arts; Creative writing--Study and teaching.; Videorecordings.
Collection Contents
- Audio recordings
  - Jean and Bill Lane Lecture Series
    - Berry, Wendell, Lane Lecture Series, 1989-03-03; 1.02; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Brodsky, Joseph, Lane Lecture Series, 1988-11-14; 1.21; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Cunningham, Michael, Lane Lecture Series, 2002-11-25; 1.01; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Eisenberg, Deborah, Lane Lecture Series, 2010-10-18; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 8)
    - Gluck, Louise, Lane Lecture Series, 2000-04-17; 2.01; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
    - Gordon, Mary, Lane Lecture Series, 2001-11-05; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Graham, Jorie, Lane Lecture Series, 2007-04-18; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 8)
    - Gunn, Thom, Lane Lecture Series, 1989-04-10; 1.14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Hass, Robert, Lane Lecture Series, 1996-11-04; 1.20; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Hecht, Anthony, Lane Lecture Series, 2002-01-28; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
    - Kelly, Brigit Pegeen, Lane Lecture Series, 2009-04-20; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 8)
    - Kennedy, Stanley, Lane Lecture Series, 1989-11-17; 3.15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Kunitz, Stanley, Lane Lecture Series, 1986-11-17; 1.13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - LeGuin, Ursula, Lane Lecture Series, 1990-04-16; 1.08; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Lessing, Doris, Lane Lecture Series, 1989-11-13; 2.02; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
    - Levertov, Denise, Lane Lecture Series, 1995-02-13; 1.16; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Lewis, Janet, Lane Lecture Series, 1990-11-05; 1.19; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Mehta, Ved, 1988-02-22; 3.17; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Moore, Brian, Lane Lecture Series, 1992-04-01; 1.07; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Oates, Joyce Carol, Lane Lecture Series, 1985-10-28; 1.12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - O'Brien, Tim, Lane Lecture Series, 2000-02-10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Paz, Octavio, Lane Lecture Series, 1988-04-18; 7.02; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 7)
    - Pinsky, Robert, Lane Lecture Series, 1998-04-06; 1.17; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Rich, Adrienne, Lane Lecture Series, 1994-11-14; 1.15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Roth, Philip, Lane Lecture Series, 1993-03-02; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Smiley, Jane, Lane Lecture Series, 2003-04-28; 2.05; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
    - Taylor, Peter, Lane Lecture Series, 1989-02-06; 1.04; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Trevor, William, Lane Lecture Series, 1991-04-01; 1.09; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Walcott, Derek, Lane Lecture Series, 1990-02-12; 1.05; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - White, Edmund, Lane Lecture Series, 1993-04-12; 2.03; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
    - Wolff, Tobias, Lane Lecture Series, 1995-04-10; 1.11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Unknown, 1993-03-02; 1.27; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - Unknown, 2000-02-10; 1.06; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
    - Unknown, Lane Lecture Series, 2001-11-05; 7.01; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 7)
    - Unknown, Lane Lecture Series, 2004-04-14; 2.04; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
    - Unknown, Lane Lecture Series, 2008-04-14; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 8)
  - Stein Visiting Writer Lecture
    - Gordon, Mary, Stein Visiting Writer Lecture, 2009-01-21; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 8)
  - Adams, Ansel & Stegner, Wallace, 1982-10-24; 1.24; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Berry, Wendell, Gaines, Ernest, & Turow, Scott, Centennial Celebration, 1989-04-30; 3.07-3.08; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Boorsin, Daniel, Kresge Auditorium, 1996-10-09; 4.04; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Carey, Peter, 1999-02-08; 3.12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Collins, Billy, 2001-09-24; 1.26; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Cunningham, Michael, 2002-11-25; 3.10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Doyle, Roddy, Unknown, 2006-11-13; 2.07; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Ford, Richard, Cubberley Auditorium, 2006-03-06; 3.13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Hansen, Ron & Wolff, Tobias, Harriett Doerr Fund Readings, 1989-04-17; 1.22; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Howe, Susan, Kresge Auditorium, 1997-02-10; 3.06; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Irving, John, Kresge Auditorium, 1997-02-18; 3.09; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Jones, Edward, reading and question and answer session, 2008-04-14, 2008-11-03; 2 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 8)
  - Kingston, Maxine Hong, Interview, 1989-11-10; 7.08; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 7)
  - Komunyakaa, Yusef, 2002-10-09; 4.05; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Le Carré, John, 1998-11-02; 3.15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Levertov, Denise & Boland, Eavan, 1997-04-28; 1.03; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - McFarland, Dennis, Annual Readings in Fiction, 1991-05-16; 4.11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - McHugh, Heather, Unknown, 2004-10-24; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - O'Connor, Frank, Dinkelspiel Auditorium, 1961-04-18; 4.01; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Olds, Sharon, 1999-04-05; 3.04; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Ondaatje, Michael, 2003-01-23; 3.11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Parker, Tom, 7.04; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 7)
  - Pierce, Gary, 2000-04-17; 2.15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Price, Richard, 1990-04-04; 7.05; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 7)
  - Riley, Judas, Cortes, Fidelito, & Harrison, Jeffrey, Stegner Fellows in Poetry, 1986-05-13; 3.16; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Roy, Arundhati, President's Reading Series, 1999-05-03; 4.03; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Sanders, George, 2009-02-02; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 8)
  - Seth, Vikram, 2001-10-17; 4.07-4.08; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Simons, Michelle and Daniel, John, Briggs Room, 1986-04-16; 4.02; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Stegner, Wallace, Interview, 1988-04-07; 7.09; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 7)
  - Stegner, Wallace, 1989-12-12; 1.18; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Stegner, Wallace, 'Fresh Air', 1992; 1.25; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Stone, Robert, 1991-04-15; 3.01; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Stone, Robert, 2000-10-19; 3.02; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Sund, Robert, W. S. Merwin, Poetry Center, 1983-04-21; 7.07; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 7)
  - Toibin, Colm, Reading, Campbell Recital Hall, 2008-01-16; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 8)
  - Turow, Scott, Annual Readings in Fiction, 1992-05-04; 3.14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Turow, Scott, Creative Writing Dinner, 1996-05-20; 3.03; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3, 7)
  - Tyler, Anne, 1990-04-26; 7.06; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 7)
  - Vaughn, Stephanie, Annual Readings in Fiction, 1990-05-09; 3.05; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Williams, C. K., Unknown, 2005-01-24; 2.06; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Unknown, Talk On Alice Walker, 1987-09-24; 1.23; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Unknown, 2003-11-10; 2.08; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Unknown, 2004-04-12; 2.09; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Unknown, 2004-11-09; 2.10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Unknown, 2005-04-18; 2.11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Unknown, 2007-01-16; 2.12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Unknown, 2007-10-23; 2.13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Unknown, 2008-02-11; 2.14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Unknown, Kresge Auditorium, 2002-01-28; 2.16; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Unknown, Kresge Auditorium, 2004-10-27; 2.17; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Unknown, Kresge Auditorium, 1997-04-14; 4.06; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Unknown, Kresge Auditorium, 1998-02-09; 4.09; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Unknown, 2000-05-16; 4.20; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Unknown, Kresge Auditorium, 2001-02-21; 4.18; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Unknown, Kresge Auditorium, 2001-02-26; 4.19; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Unknown, Kresge Auditorium, 2001-03-07; 4.15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Unknown, Kresge Auditorium, 2001-04-16; 4.13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Unknown, Kresge Auditorium, 2001-10-25; 2.10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Unknown, Kresge Auditorium, 2003-02-03; 4.12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Unknown, Kresge Auditorium, 2005-04-05; 4.16-4.17; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Unknown, Kresge Auditorium, 2006-01-23; 4.14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Unknown, Annual Readings in Fiction, 1989-04-17; 7.03; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 7)
  - Unknown, 2005-06-01; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 8)
- Video recordings
  - Lane Lecture Series
    - Le Carré, John, Lane Lecture Series, 1998-11-02; 5.09; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
    - Lewis, Janet, Lane Lecture Series, 1990-11-05; 6.10; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
    - Mathiessen, Peter, Lane Lecture Series, 1999-03-24; 5.10; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
    - O'Brien, Tim, Lane Lecture Series, 2000-02-10; 5.11; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
    - Olds, Sharon, Lane Lecture Series, 1999-05-04; 6.11; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
    - Paley, Grace, Lane Lecture Series, 1998-02-01; 5.12; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
    - Pinsky, Robert, Lane Lecture Series, 1998-06-01; 5.13; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Alexie, Sherman, President's Reading Series, 1999-10-25; 6.01; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Boorstin, Daniel, 1996-10-09; 6.02; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Campo, Rafael, President's Reading Series, 2001-01-30; 5.01; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Campo, Rafael, A Reading, 2001-02-14; 5.02; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Carey, Peter, Arts at Stanford, 5.03; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Chang, Lan Samantha, Stanford Authors, 1998-10-01; 5.04; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Conroy, Frank, Charlie Rose, "Body and Soul", 6.03; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Dove, Rita, Arts at Stanford, 5.05; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Goodman, Allegra, President's Reading Series, 2000-01-19; 6.04; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Kingston, Maxine Hong, Another Book Peace, 2001-03-07; 5.06; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Kingston, Maxine Hong, 5.07; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Lee, Li-Young, President's Reading Series, 1999-01-20; 5.08; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - An Evening of Poetry with Boland, Eavan and Levertov, Denise, 1997-02-01; 6.12; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Morrison, Toni, MacNeil-Lehrer News Hour, 1988-03-31; 6.07; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Pollia, Muriel, Pollia Summer Fellowships Luncheon, 2006-05-25; 6.08; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Roy, Arundhati, President's Reading Series, 1999-05-03; 5.14; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Stegner, Wallace, Kepler's Bookstore, 1990-07-01; 6.09; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Tribute to Denise Levertov, 1998-03; 6.05; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Turow, Scott: A Reading, 2000-04-03; 6.06; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Welty, Eudora, 1989-01-01; 6.13; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Unknown, 6.14; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Unknown, 6.15; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
- Photographs, 2005-06-01; 32 computer file(s) (JPG)